
Write-Output needs at least one thing to actually write. If you give it nothing, it will start asking. To create an empty file (i.e. actually write nothing at all, similar to touch) you can use Set-Content -Path xxx -Value $null. Write-Output $null is also allowed, of course. – 
Sudha

So are InputObject and Path asking for values to enter into the file? Because nothing I enter against them gets written to it, and I cannot get the command to end without pressing ctrl+c – 
Sudha
 
InputObject asks for the value to write, while Path asks for the name of the file. 
